（ナレーション）アポロが
月着陸を果たしてから ほぼ１世紀
It has been roughly one century since the Apollo moon landing.
人類初の木星往還船
フォン･ブラウン号が―
Humanity's first exploration ship to Jupiter, the Von Braun, is preparing to set sail,
旅立とうとしていました
人類の夢と野心を乗せて
...carrying with it humanity's hopes and dreams.
（医師）まだですか？
Aren't you done yet?
I'm sorry, ma'am.
（保安官１）申し訳ありません
（保安官２）宇宙防衛戦線の
メンバーだったんですよ
Hakim Ashmead was a member of the Space Defense Front.
ハキム･アシュミードは
（ギガルト）くく… んん…
（保安官２）最初から
フォン･ブラウン号を狙って―
His goal all along was to take the crew test to get a shot at the Von Braun.
乗員試験を受けたんです
（保安官３）以前 通信衛星を―
You remember that terrorist attack where they tried to slam...
ISPV-７に衝突させようとした
テロがありましたね
...that communications satellite into ISPV-7, don't you?
あれも調査の結果 彼が保安情報を
流していたことが分かりました
Based on our investigation, we've learned he had been...
...leaking them information from the OSA in that incident, as well.
He was working as a terrorist the whole time he was in the OSA.
（保安官２）
軌道保安庁に入ったときから―
テロリストだったんですよ 彼は
He's been at large ever since his attempt to destroy the Von Braun failed.
（保安官３）
彼は フォン･ブラウン号の―
破壊に失敗したあと
いまだ逃走中です 恐らく…
We believe that he is on the moon.
（ギガルト）どうして…
- Why?
We'd like you to tell us everything that you know about him.
- Why couldn't I think of one for him?
どうして 浮かばなかったのかな
It's your duty as a fellow member of the OSA.
- Why couldn't I come up with a nickname?
あいつのあだ名…
♪～
♪そして人は時空(とき)を
越えた夢を見る
Soshite hito wa toki wo koeta yume wo miru
And people dream dreams that transcend time.
♪静寂の宇宙(うみ)に抱かれて
seijyaku no umi ni idakarete
Held in the depths of the sea.
♪鳥や雲を見上げては
tori ya kumo wo miagete wa
As they look up at the stars and clouds.
♪儚(はかな)い生命(いのち)燃やした
hakanai inochi moyashita ikusen no asa ni
It set their ephemeral souls on fire on a thousand mornings.
♪幾千の朝に
♪光が向かう場所へ
hikari ga mukau basho he habataku darou
I bet they're taking right to where the light is headed.
♪羽ばたくだろう
♪願いを放つ時は今
daichi wo ima tori yoku kette
Now kickoff from the ground like a bird.
♪果てなき夢を乗せた
hatenaki yume wo noseta furontia he
Off into the frontier that is carrying boundless dreams.
♪フロンティアへ
♪遠く遠く Dive in the Sky
tooku tooku dive in the sky
Farther and farther dive in the sky.
Phase 22
Exposure
Why am I being taken off the flight?!
（チェンシン）
どうして僕が外されるんですか？
Standard procedure is to have the same crew on the flight out and back again, isn't it?
行きと帰りは
同じクルーで組むのが原則でしょ
納得できません！
It doesn't make any sense!
What it means is, go cool your head.
（船長）頭を冷やせということだ
何にイラついてんのか知らんが―
I don't know what's gotten you so angry, but you've been acting strange lately.
最近のお前は どこかおかしいぞ
（チェンシン）
おかしいって どこがですか？
Strange?! Strange how?!
（船長）それだよ それ
This. This right here. You never used to raise your voice like this.
前は そんなふうに
声を荒げるやつじゃなかった
（チェンシン）ああ…
今のままでは
君に人の命を預けられない
The way you're acting now, I can't trust you with other people's lives.
That's the call I've made as the ship's captain.
それが船長である私の判断だ
Go relearn your job on a freighter.
貨物船で勉強し直せ
Come on.
おい
（チェンシン）んっ…
うっ く…
ん？
It was my decision, wasn't it?
What's the point of talking it over with you?
（ハチマキ）俺のことだろ
お前に話してどうすんだよ
I have my own life.
And you have your own, right?
（ハチマキ）
俺は俺 お前はお前だろ？
（ユーリ）
いや まいったよ タナベ
This is most ridiculous, Tanabe.
The paperwork has become quite complicated thanks to the INTO Supreme Council meeting.
連合の最高評議会のせいで
手続きが複雑になってて―
課長たちの定期便も
少し遅れるみたいだから―
It sounds like the shuttle carrying the Chief and the others is going to be a little late,
...so you can go ahead and take off early.
今日はもう 先に上がってても…
タナベ
Tanabe?
（タナベ）はっ！ あっ はい
あっ 何でしょうか？
Yes? What is it?
Did you try calling the security company?
（チャド）
警備会社には かけてみたか？
They said that everyone is out handling security for the Supreme Council meeting!
（社員１）それが
評議会の警備で出払ってるって
（社員２）
３時に用意できた？ よし
You got 30 for us? Great!
Yeah, I think we can make do with these prices here.
（社員３）
ええ なんとか この値段でも―
受けてもらえそうです
（フィー）へえ
ここが人類の未来を懸けた
木星計画の運営会社とはねえ
Hard to believe that this is the management company...
...that's running the Jupiter project that humanity is pinning its future on.
Because we can't spare any time to worry about how we look.
（ドルフ）
体裁にこだわる余裕はないからな
This may be the Jupiter project, but it's not a high-priority item inside INTO.
木星計画といっても―
連合の中のプライオリティーは
さして高くない
The budget is as large as you'd expect,
but most of the money has strings attached.
予算の規模は それなりだが
ほとんどは ひも付き
Hardly any funds in the budget are discretionary.
自由になる予算は ごくわずかだ
Of course, I plan to cut the majority of those strings...
（ドルフ）もっとも
大半のひもは断ち切ってやるが
（フィー）ウッフフフフ…
（ドルフ）うん？
I like that look on your face, Dolf.
いい顔してるよ ドルフ
（ドルフ）ん？
You're definitely cut out out for playing
David to somebody else's Goliath.
やっぱり 大きな相手に
立ち向かうほうが―
あんたに向いてるよ
（ドルフ）んんっ
星野(ほしの)君のことで来たんだろ？
You came here to ask about that Hoshino-kun, right?
（フィー）え？
（ドルフ）３次試験の受験者は―
The people taking the third round of tests are effectively incommunicado.
基本的に
外部と連絡が取れないからな
心配なんだろ？
You're worried, right?
I don't really care about the test results one way or the other.
テストの結果は
どっちでもいいんだけど―
あいつがつきあってる相手が
ちょっとね
I'm more worried about the girl he's going out with.
You're a good leader.
You care about your people.
（ドルフ）部下思いのいい上司だ
あんたもね
So are you.
Just give them some spiel about improving their image.
イメージアップとか何とか言って…
Chad looks like a whole new man compared to when he was at Technora.
チャドのやつ
テクノーラのときと 全然 違う
I don't intend to let any of
my valuable resources sit and rot.
せっかくの人材を
腐らせるつもりはない
反省だよ
I regret that I let that happen. And that
I didn't use Debris Section properly.
デブリ課を
きちんと使いこなせなかったことの
Even if he passed a difficult test,
he's still a failure as a human being.
いくら難しい試験に受かっても
人間として失格だよ
Now I think I understand why you broke up with him.
君が別れた理由も
今なら分かる気がするね
（クレア）いい顔になったじゃない
That's a good look for you.
えっ？
You have a nice face and body, you've got a good head on your shoulders,
（クレア）容姿端麗 頭脳明晰
...and to top it all off, you come from a wealthy family and you have a good personality.
その上 富豪のお坊ちゃんで
性格もいい
正直 うそくさいやつだって
思ってたわ
To tell you the truth, I always thought you were too good to be true.
（チェンシン）クレア 今日は
随分と意地が悪いじゃないか
You're awfully mean-spirited today, Claire.
知らなかったでしょ？
You never knew, did you?
I hated you with every fiber of my being.
私 あなたのこと 大嫌いだったの
（チェンシン）あっ
You see yourself as a considerate man.
That's horrible.
（クレア）自分のことを
思いやりのある人間だと思っている
醜悪よね
I don't think like that!
（チェンシン）僕は別に…
（クレア）気を配っているつもりで
あなたは 肝心なところで鈍いのよ
You think you're sensitive, but you're awfully dense where it really counts.
私のことも ハチのことも
何も分かってない
You don't know the first thing about me or Hachi.
（チェンシン）人のことなんて…
You can never really know someone.
Claire Rondo, employed with the Debris
Section of Technora's Second Division?
（保安官）テクノーラ社
第２事業部デブリ課の―
クレア･ロンドさんですね
軌道保安庁まで
ご同行願えますか？
Would you mind coming with us to the Orbital Security Agency?
何の容疑ですか？
What do you want with me?
（保安官）誤解しないでください
任意同行ですよ
Please don't get the wrong impression.
This is purely voluntary.
ハキム･アシュミードの件と言えば
分かっていただけますか？
Would you agree to come in if I said that it was about Hakim Ashmead?
ええ 分かりました
All right, I understand.
あっ あ…
この世界には あなたの知らない
黒くて汚いことがいっぱいあるのよ
There are lots and lots of dark, dirty secrets in this world that you don't know anything about.
The Sea of Tranquility Office of
Development Promotion has...
Yes, the people from Second Division are here.
（受付）はい 第２事業部の方が
Yes, the Debris Section reinforcements.
はい デブリ課の応援です
ええ エレベーターでそちらに
Yes, they're taking the elevator up.
I wonder if this is gonna work out?
（課長）
うまくやっていけるかな
少なくとも１か月は
一緒に仕事するわけだし
We're going to be working
together for at least a month.
（ラビィ）大丈夫ですって
It'll be fine! Debris Sections are the
lowest performers in every division.
デブリ課は
どこの事業部だって成績最下位
お荷物部署ですよ
As departments go, we're all dead weight.
（課長）でもさあ
レベルＢだよ 受付から３階も上
Yes, but they're on Level B. That's three floors above the reception desk!
Our office is way down in a basement storage room!
僕たちは地下の倉庫なのに
（ラビィ）
課長 そんなに心配しなくても―
Stop worrying so much, Chief!
打ち解けるための一発ネタに
抜かりはありません
I brought along the perfect gag to break the ice!
はい
Look!
プッ ヒャハハハハ…
What in the world is that supposed to be?
何だい？ それ
（ラビィ）いいでしょ？
絶対にウケますって
Isn't it great?
It'll go over like gangbusters!
ご希望とあらば
最高評議会で前座を務めても…
If they asked me to, I could even be the opening act for the Supreme Council meeting!
あれ？
Huh?
Is this really their Debris Section?
It's so neat and tidy.
ここって ほんとにデブリ課？
なんか きれい
（ラビィ）やっぱり 現場組を―
Maybe we really should've brought along our field team, too...
連れてきたほうが
よかったですかね
せめて 菓子折りでも
Or at least an introductory gift...
（課長）
今からじゃ 遅刻になっちゃうよ
We'd be late if we went and bought something now.
ほら こういう
きちんとした部署って―
Tidy offices like this are always sticklers for punctuality, you know?
時間にもうるさいから
（ラビィ）
では 私が買ってきますから―
Then I'll go buy something myself!
You go on without me, Chief!
課長 お先に
I don't want to go in alone!
I'll go buy the gift!
（課長）１人でなんて嫌だよ
だったら僕が買ってくるから
そんな 課長に行かせるなんて
I couldn't possibly ask you to run an errand, Chief!
いやいや 僕が
（ラビィ）いえ 私が
No, no! I'll do it!
No, I will!
（エーデル）ほれ
Get moving.
（課長･ラビィ）わああーっ
I'm so sorry!
ごめんなさーい
（ラビィ）わああーっ
（クラッカーの音）
（課長）はああ
（ラビィ）ぐええ…
（課員たちの拍手と歓声）
Welcome to Debris Section!
（課員１）ようこそ デブリ課へ
（クラッカーの音）
C-Chief?
か… 課長
うん うん
（課員２）
歓迎しま～す 第２事業部の皆さん
A hearty welcome to all our friends from the Second Division!
I guess Debris Sectons are
Debris Sections no matter where you go.
やっぱりデブリ課は
デブリ課だねえ ヘヘッ
（エーデル）ハァ…
（保安官１）
成績は 軌道保安庁 入庁以来―
He maintained a top-class record ever since he joined the OSA.
トップクラスを維持
He won the Jim Lovell Award in 2073.
2073年には
ジムラベル賞を受賞している
Hakim Ashmead was an exemplary member of the OSA.
ハキム･アシュミードは
極めて模範的な隊員だった
His circle of social aquaintances was broad, but shallow.
（保安官１）
交際範囲は広く浅く―
ご丁寧に
温暖化防止運動にも参加して―
He was even careful enough to be involved in Greenhouse Effect Prevention activism.
表向きは
宇宙開発支持者を装っていた
On the surface, he was a proponent of space development.
He had everyone totally...
まったく大した…
うん
星野八郎太(はちろうた)さん
ご協力ありがとうございました
Hoshino Hachirota-san,
thank you for your cooperation.
もうお帰りになって結構です
所持品は受付で
You're free to go now.
Pick up your belongings at the front desk.
Also, this matter isn't to be discussed with anyone.
あっ あと この件はご内密に
ご家族にも累が及ぶ可能性が
It's possible that your family might be put at risk.
分かっています
I know, I know!
これで試験に戻っても
いいんですよね
I can get back to my testing now, right?
（保安官１）
その件については 連絡待ちです
As for that, please wait until we contact you.
あっ
Claire?
クレア
What're you...
あっ な…
You're worried about me?
（クレア）心配してくれるの？
It's all right. For the moment,
I'm cooperating voluntarily.
大丈夫 今のところ任意同行だから
けど…
Yeah, but...
私を 宇宙防衛戦線の
メンバーだと思ってるのよ
They think that I'm a member of the Space Defense Front.
What?
何？ 何言ってんだ おい
What're you guys talking about?
That's the stupidest thing I've ever heard!
そんなバカなこと
（保安官２）星野さん
Hoshino-san...
（ハチマキ）そんなことあるか！
She'd never do that!
It's because I'm Hakim Ashmead's girlfriend.
（クレア）私が
ハキム･アシュミードの女だから
えっ
That's what you think, isn't it?
（クレア）
そういうことなんでしょ？
（保安官３）詳しいことは
取調室でお話しします
Let's talk about the details in the interview room, all right?
（ハチマキ）おい
Hey!
Does that bother you?
気になる？
（ハチマキ）そりゃ
Of course it does!
あなたには
タナベさんがいるでしょ
You have Tanabe-san, don't you?
みんな 中途半端に優しくて
No one ever fully commits with their feelings...
（保安官２）
くれぐれも ご内密にお願いします
Again, everything we discussed is to remain confidential.
Yeah, sure...
（ハチマキ）ああ
（八郎太）
結局 人間は１人なんだよ
In the end, humans are all alone.
自分は自分 他人は他人
You have your own life, and other people have their own.
You said the same thing to Tanabe, remember?
お前だって
タナベにそう言ったろ？
だったら
なぜ ハキムに腹を立てる？
So why are you so pissed off at Hakim for?
Basically, you were pinning your hopes on him.
要するに
お前は ハキムにすがってたんだ
一緒に木星へ行ってくれるやつが
欲しかったんだ
You wanted somebody who would make the trip to Jupiter with you.
チェンシンは違った
けど ハキムなら…
Cheng-Shin couldn't have done it.
But Hakim, he could've.
残念だったな
Gee, that's too bad.
And just when you thought you'd made yourself a friend, too...
せっかく仲間ができたと
思ったのになあ
結局 １人なんだ 人間は
When it's all said and done, people are alone.
ひしめき合うように見える
夜空の星だって―
Even those stars that seem to be packed shoulder to shoulder in the night sky...
...are actually separated by vast distances.
実際には 遠く離れているものさ
In between those stars, there's nothing but dark, cold, cruel space.
星々の間には―
暗くて寒くて
残酷な宇宙が広がってる
（リュシー）あっ
（コリン）うん？
What's the matter?
（コリン）どうしたの？
いいえ
知り合いがいたような気がして
Nothing, I just thought that
I saw someone I knew.
（ハチマキ）あっ…
バッカか 俺は 今更…
What am I, some kind of moron?
How can I talk to her now?
あれ？
Huh?
（太郎坊(たろうぼう)）ああっ
（ハチマキ）あんた 確か…
Wait, your name's...
（太郎坊）えーっと 太郎坊です
Um, it's Tarobo.
（ハチマキ）
ああ そんな名前だったな
Right, that was your name...
Where are the other ninjas?
Are they around?
他の忍者は？ いるのかい？
（太郎坊）ご… ごめんなさい
（ハチマキ）えっ？
I-I'm sorry!
Please, pretend you didn't see this!
（太郎坊）見逃してください
お金ないから 仕事なくて
I don't have a job, so I don't have any money...
So please... Please...
だから だから…
（太郎坊）
死んじゃって 僕以外のみんな
They're all dead.
Everyone but me.
（ハチマキ）死んだ！？
They're dead?!
（太郎坊）
タンデムミラーエンジンの―
They had gotten jobs working on the tandem mirror engine.
仕事をしてたんだ
ああっ
（太郎坊）
僕 ホテルの火事のときに
おじけづいてしまって １人だけ
Back during that hotel fire,
I was the only one who was afraid...
Ever since, we've had a bit of a falling out.
They didn't ask me to come along to work.
…で それ以来
気まずくなっちゃって―
仕事に誘ってもらえなかったんだ
Sign: Matter is void, all is vanity
（ハチマキ）…で あんたは
ここで何をしてたんだ？
So, what were you doing in here?
（太郎坊）ええ… え…
遺品を売ってたのか
You were selling off their stuff?
（太郎坊）ううう…
ああ あの…
Um...
いいよ
It's okay.
I don't expect any better from human beings.
そんなもんだろう 人なんて
（戸の開閉音）
ああ…
う… うん うん…
Well, I guess I can come up with some way to make the deadline,
（ゴロー）
まっ なんとか間に合わせるけどよ
...but don't make any more sudden changes to the schedule, okay?
（ゴロー）いきなり
スケジュールを変更すんのは―
今度から なしにしてくれ
（ロックスミス）
スケジュールを前倒しして―
Moving up the schedule and taking the ship down into lunar orbit...
月周回軌道に降りろってのは
スポンサーの要望ですからね
...was a request on the part of our sponsor.
約束はできませんよ
I can't make any promises in that regard.
（ゴロー）ヘッ 見え見えなんだよ
マスコミに見せつけようってのが
Geez, it's so obvious that they wanna show off to the media.
何が宇宙で初めての
最高評議会だっての
"The first Supreme Council meeting in space,"
my ass...
ああ それと
船長は いつ来るんだ？
Hey, and when's the captain coming? I heard that you're gonna be staying behind on Earth.
あんたは地球に残るってのによ
The President says that he'll arrive when the people who passed the test are announced.
試験の合格者発表に合わせるって
社長さんが言うんでね
（ゴロー）ふーん
あら
Oops.
You said that you've had that hook for many years, didn't you?
年季が入ってそうですね
（ゴロー）ああ 俺が初めて
火星に行ったときから―
Yeah, I've been using this ever since my first flight to Mars.
使ってるからなあ
I was with Gigalt on that trip.
ギガルトと一緒だった
（リポーター）
史上初 地球外での―
With the historic first meeting of the Supreme
Council to be held here in two days,
連合最高評議会を２日後に控え―
ここ 月ステーションは
緊迫した雰囲気に包まれています
...the atmosphere here at the lunar station is tense.
It looks like Chairman Clifford has arrived!
He is surrounded by his bodyguards!
ボディーガードに
付き添われながら…
Look at that! He's waving cheerfully at the press corps!
（秘書）開催地を静(しず)かの海(うみ)市から
月ステーションに変えたのは―
Moving the meeting from Sea of Tranquility City to the lunar station was a drastic measure.
英断でしたね
（クリフォード）わざわざ
月面などに降りなくても―
There's no need to go all the way down to the lunar surface.
宇宙で会議を行ったという
結果があればいい
All that matters is that we held the meeting in space.
はい セキュリティーも
強化しやすいですし―
Yes, sir.
I suppose that it's also easier to beef up security here,
...and it's probably also forced those terrorists to change their plans.
テロリストどもも 計画の変更を
余儀なくされたでしょうね
The number of security personnel on the lunar station is nearly triple what it was a month ago.
（組織員１）
月ステーションの警備員は―
ひと月前のおよそ３倍です
On the other hand, security in Sea of
Tranquility City is now short-handed.
（組織員２）
その分 静かの海市の警備は手薄に
（コートの男）
軌道保安庁の巡視船は―
73% of the OSA's patrol vessels are gathered in lunar orbit,
73パーセントが
月周回軌道に集結
...checking out every satellite and piece of debris that they come across.
周辺の衛星やデブリを
手当たりしだいに洗っています
（白猫）先日のISPV-７を
狙った作戦が効いたようだな
It looks like our recent operation against
ISPV-7 had an effect on them.
Yes. It's made our work here much easier.
はい おかげでこちらの仕掛けが
やりやすくなりました
マタタビの準備もできています
The work on Catnip is finished. They say it can cover all of lunar orbit for 40 minutes.
月軌道を40分はカバーできると
How about the Black Cats?
（白猫）黒猫はどうだ？
We've gathered six.
We think we can get one or two more.
（組織員２）６匹まで集まりました
あと１～２匹は増やせるかと
The Tiger has begun its descent into lunar orbit.
（組織員３）トラは
月軌道への降下を始めています
全て予定どおりです
Everything is going according to plan.
（白猫）気取られるなよ
Don't do anything to raise their suspicions.
With our inferior numbers, our only chance of victory is with a sneak attack.
戦力の少ない我々が勝つには
奇襲しかない
（ラビィ）
よう ハチマキじゃないかあ
Well, I'll be! It's Hachimaki!
What're you doing here?
（ハチマキ）わあっ
何やってんだ こんなとこで
おい
Hey!
Ha-chan! Long time, no see!
ハッちゃん 久しぶり ハハッ
聞いたよ
３次試験までいったんだって？
We heard that you've made it all the way to the third round of testing!
こいつもねえ デブリ屋なんだよ
This joker is a fellow debris hauler!
フォン･ブラウン号の試験に
受かったんだぞ
He passed the test for the Von Braun!
（一同のどよめき）
（ラビィ）
まあ 私の指導のたまものでして
Well, it's all thanks to my guidance, of course.
なあ ハチ ワハハハハ…
Isn't that right, Hachi?
（一同の笑い声）
Hoshino-san.
星野さん
（ハチマキ）あ？
Tanabe-san is working hard.
（エーデル）
タナベさん 頑張ってますよ
（ハチマキ）あっ…
She said that she'll do the job right even if you aren't there.
星野さんがいなくても
ちゃんとやってみせるって
That she'd give it her best even on her own.
１人でも頑張るんだって
ハチ 一度ぐらい会社に来いよ
Hachi! Stop by the office sometime!
お前宛てのメールとか
たまってるしさ
You've got a lot of mail piling up!
仕事のやつはいいんだけど
プライベートのもあってな
You don't need to worry about the work-related stuff, but there's some personal e-mails, too.
ごめんね ハッちゃん
We're sorry, Ha-chan.
緊急の用事だと困るから
確認させてもらったんだ
We took the liberty of looking through them to make sure there wasn't anything urgent.
（ハチマキ）あっ ああ…
メール 誰からだった？
That's okay.
Who were the e-mails from?
（ラビィ）警備課とか資材課とか
多分 男子寮の連中だろうなあ
They're mostly from Maintence and Records, so they're probably from your dorm buddies.
あと ギガルトさんからも
There was one from Gigalt-san, too.
From Sensei? What did it say?
先生から？ 何て？
It said to come to Sea of Tranquility Medical
Center once you were done with your tests.
（課長）試験が終わったら
静かの海総合病院に来いって
The hospital?
病院？
♪～
（ハチマキ）読む？
（ノノ）あっ…
Wanna read this?
It's this week's Cosmonauts.
I already read it.
「コスモノーツ」の今週号
俺 もう読んじゃったから
フフッ ありがと ハチマキ 診察？
Thanks, Hachimaki.
Getting a check-up?
No, I'm here to visit somebody.
ギガルトさん？
Gigalt-san?
知ってるの？
You know him?
（ノノ）うん
Yeah...
俺のＥＶＡの先生なんだ
He taught me all I know about EVA.
殺しても
死なないような人なんだけど―
He's the kind of guy who's too tough to die.
年かね 入院なんてさ
Still, I guess he's getting on in years if he's in the hospital.
メールには―
His e-mail said to come see him once I was finished with testing.
試験が終わってから来いって
書いてあったんだけど―
どの部屋か分かる？
Do you know which room he's in?
（ノノ）あ…
これ 渡してくれって
ギガルトさんから
Here. Gigalt-san said to give this to you.
ああ？
何だ 先生 もういないの？
What, Sensei's not around anymore?
No. He's gone.
（ノノ）うん もういない
何だ ほんと元気な人だな
Geez, that's one spry old geezer.
ノノ 変なあだ名とか
付けられなかった？
Did he give you a weird nickname, Nono?
ハチマキ あのね…
Hachimaki, what I meant was...
Nono-chan, it's time for your check-up.
（看護師）
ノノちゃん 検査の時間よ
（ノノ）あっ でも…
B-But...
I have the day off, so I'll wait for you until you're done.
今日 オフだから
終わるまで待ってるよ
（ノノ）あっ そう？
You will?
えっ 先輩と会ったんですか？
What? You ran into Senpai?
Yep, we ran smack into him on our way back from our first round of bar hopping...
うん １次会の帰りにね バッタリ
（課長）
愛(あい)ちゃん ２次会だよ おいでー
Ai-chan! Come join us for round two!
来ないの？ 来なさいよ
Will you come? C'mon over!
えっ？ どこ行ったかって？
What's that? Where did he go?
Beats me, maybe he went back to his place.
知らないなあ
家に帰ったんじゃないの？
（課長）ラビィちゃん
あれだよ ほら あそこ
Lavie-chan! You remember!
He went to what's-it-called...
おい 私だ こら
Hey. It's me, dammit.
あっ エーデル？
Edel?
（エーデル）イエス
Yes!
Are you drunk?
飲み過ぎじゃあ
（エーデル）
シングルモルト ダブルで12杯
I've had 12 single malt doubles.
But that's not important, he's at the hospital!
ああ そんなことより 病院
（タナベ）えっ？
（エーデル）
ハチ野郎は 静かの海総合病院
That bozo Hachi's at Sea of
Tranquility Medical Center!
今から追いかけりゃあ
きっと会える
If you leave now, you can still catch him there!
（エーデル）そこからなら
第１フロアに上って―
From where you are, the fastest way is to go up to the first floor...
宇宙航前から出てる
シャトルバスが早い
...and take the shuttle bus from the spaceport!
走れば 47分のに間に合う 急げ
If you run, you can still make the 7:47 bus! Get moving!
（タナベ）ありがとう エーデル
Thanks, Edel.
（ハチマキ）あっ…
あ…
あっ
（タナベ）１人で生きて
１人で死んで １人で…
Living alone and dying alone...
Alone...
なんで満足できるんですか？
バカみたい
How could anyone be satisfied with that?
It's stupid...
（ハチマキ）んっ…
Hey, that's Sensei...
（ハチマキ）これ 先生？
（ギガルト）
久しぶりだな ハチマキ
It's been a long time, Hachimaki.
あっ…
If you're watching this video,
it means that I'm probably dead.
お前がこいつを見てるってことは
多分 俺は死んでるな
（ハチマキ）ああっ…
It's cancer. Well, for us astronauts, it's like an occupational hazard.
（ギガルト）ガンだよ
まあ 宇宙飛行士にとっちゃ
職業病みたいなもんだ
I guess that's the kind of place that space is. You know?
宇宙ってのは
そういう所だろう なあ？
I heard that Harry Rowland, my own Sensei, died here, too.
俺の先生のハリー･ローランドも
ここで死んだって聞いた
Space is such a cold place...
宇宙ってのは冷たいよなあ
And it's cruel. And it's heartless.
残酷だよな つれないよな
でも 引かれちまうんだよな
But we fall in love with her, anyway.
性悪女にホレた純情男みたいに
Like a pure-hearted boy falling for a bad girl.
ハハハ… まあ これも
ホレた弱味ってやつか
I guess this is what they mean by loving something, warts and all.
ハハハッ ハハハハ…
So anyway, what's this I hear about you taking the test for the Von Braun?
そういや お前―
フォン･ブラウン号の試験を
受けるんだって？
ハキムから聞いた
I heard about it from Hakim.
（ハチマキ）ああっ…
He's a tough guy, isn't he?
（ギガルト）
手ごわいだろう？ あいつは
お前のいいライバルになる
He'll make a good rival for you.
ああ それと―
Oh. One more thing.
I've got one last lesson to teach you.
It's very important.
最後に
大事なことを教えといてやる
船には港が必要だ
Every ship needs a harbor.
いつまでも待ち続けてくれて―
They need a harbor that will always be there waiting for them,
最後には自分を受け止めてくれる
そんな港がな
...and will take them in when they finally arrive.
覚えておけ
Remember that.
じゃ ゴローによろしく
Well, give my best to Goro.
We'd both get all maudlin.
あいつだってテレくさいんだ
仲良くやれよ
I want you two to try to get along.
はっ 誰？
Who's there?!
（ハキム）私だ
It's me.
（アナウンス）
内科外来のニイデ先生 ニイデ先生
Paging Niide-sensei of the outpatient clinic.
Paging Niide-sensei.
至急 薬局までいらしてください
Please come to the pharmacy immediately.
（タナベ）あっ
Senpai!
先輩！
よかった 捜してたんですよ
Thank goodness! I've been looking everywhere for you!
I had to see you and talk to you.
どうしても会って話したくて
みんな心配してます
Everyone's worried about you. You haven't called, so we didn't know how you were doing.
連絡がないから
どうしてるのかって
あの… 先輩
Um, Senpai...
あんなのうそですよね？
That was a lie, right?
About being okay with being alone.
１人でいいなんて
１人きりなんて寂しすぎます
Life's too lonely to go through it all alone.
（ハチマキ）先生が…
Sensei, he's...
えっ？
（ハチマキ）ギガルト先生が…
Gigalt Sensei is...
そんな… まだ大丈夫だって
He can't be! He said he was still fine!
（ハチマキ）ああっ… まだ？
"Still"?
あっ…
（ハチマキ）タナベ お前
Tanabe, you...
あっ…
Did you know about this?
You knew Sensei had cancer?
知ってたのか？ 先生がガンだって
（タナベ）あっ あの…
Um...
（ハチマキ）
知ってて 黙ってたのか
You knew, and you didn't say anything?
You didn't tell me?
俺に…
（八郎太）
ほーら 言ったとおりだ
See, it's just like I said.
People say they like you and they love you, but this is what they do.
好きだの愛だの言ったって
こんなものさ
フッフフフ…
ギガルトさんが
先輩には黙っててほしいって
Gigalt-san said that he didn't want me to say anything to you.
でも 言い訳ですよね そんなの
But that's just an excuse, I guess...
People, stars, there's no difference.
（八郎太）
人も星も変わりゃしない
They just float there, all alone in the vastness of space.
広い宇宙に
ポツンと浮かんでるだけだ
I'm sorry, Senpai.
悲しいし 寂しいし
怒ってると思います
I bet you're feeling sad, hurt, and angry...
There's nothing but cold, cruel, dark space between you and Tanabe, too.
（八郎太）
お前とタナベの間にだって―
冷たく残酷な
暗い宇宙が広がってるのさ
（タナベ）
でも そういうのって―
But I think that you can make things like that a little easier to bear by sharing them.
分かち合うことで 少しは
軽くすることができると思うんです
１人ではつらいことだって
２人なら…
Something that might be too hard to bear alone might be easier with two people...
And you're gonna realize that you're gonna die alone.
（八郎太）そして気付くのさ
所詮 １人で死んでいくことに
ギガルトのように
Just like Gigalt.
先輩！
Senpai!
うるせえ！
Shut the hell up!
（たたく音）
（ハチマキ）全部 俺のもんだ
It's all mine!
All the loneliness! All the pain!
All the doubts! All the regrets!
孤独も 苦痛も 不安も 後悔も
もったいなくってな
You don't deserve them!
No way in hell am I gonna give 'em away to you!
てめえなんかに やれるかよ！
♪～
♪グッと水を飲み干し
gutto mizu wo nomihoshi
We gulp down some water
♪夕焼け雲見上げるのさ
yuuyakegumo miageru no sa
and look up at the evening clouds.
♪今日も一日が終わって
kyou mo ichinichi ga owatte
Let's wind our way home under the roadside trees as another day ends.
♪街路樹の下を帰ろう
gairoju no shita wo kaerou
♪やることだらけで
テンパって、
yaru koto darake de tenpatte
Even if life's so hectic that our tempers flare,
♪無理をして、
つまずいても
muri wo shite tsumazuite mo
we push ourselves too hard, and we stumble,
♪何か必ず
つかんでるさ
nani ka kanarazu tsukanderu sa
I know there'll be something to grab hold of.
♪気楽にいこうぜ
kiraku ni ikou ze
Let's move on without a care in our hearts.
♪素晴らしい人生だから
subarashii jinsei dakara
It's a wonderful life.
♪自分を愛する
勇気を持とう
jibun wo aisuru yuuki wo motou
So let's have the courage to love ourselves.
♪新しいドア叩いて
atarashii doa tataite
Let's take it one step at a time,
♪ひとつひとつ
歩いてゆこう
hitotsu hitotsu aruite yukou
knocking on new doors on the way.
♪素晴らしい人生なのさ
subarashii jinsei na no sa
It's a wonderful life.
♪君も僕もすべての人も
kimi mo boku mo subete no hito mo
You and I and everyone else
♪喜びと悲しみの意味
yorokobi to kanashimi no imi
Keep on searching for the meaning
♪探しつづけて
so just on my way
sagashitsuzukete so just on my way
Of joy and sadness, so just on my way.
Next Time
Debris Cluster
（管制官１）
一般通信チャンネルに―
We're getting interference across all regular comm channels!
障害発生
範囲は月軌道一体
多元位相干渉と思われます
It's extending across all of lunar orbit! We believe it to be multi-source phase interference.
（男性１）ナブスターの
ネットワーク自体の―
So the interference is in the
Navstar network itself?!
障害なんだな？
（男性２）そうです
That's right.
（男性３）管理会社の
ナブスターラインから―
Has there been any word through the administration company's...
今回の障害について
何か連絡はあったのか？
...Navstar help line about the interference?
（管制官２）
現在 原因箇所の調査中と
They're currently trying to...
（管制官３）
間違いなく―
It's definitely being...
ナブスターの
通信ネットワークの障害…
Dad, Mom, they say I'll be well enough to go on vacation next week.
（ノノ）来週のお休み
大丈夫だって
（ノノの母親）じゃあ
氷のクレートにでも―
Why don't we all go to the ice crater, then?
みんなで行こうか
（ノノ）
本当？ やったー！
Really? Yahoo!